ILGWU Local 262 Minutes 5780/025
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Local 262 Minutes
1943-1967
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/025
3 cubic feet
3 linear ft.
Records.
Consists of minutes from Local 262's Executive Board, Membership, Pressers Branch, and Welfare Fund Committee meetings.
5490743
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, September 26, 2008
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 02, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
Local 262 of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), also known as the Union de la Robe or the Dressmakers Union, was based in Montreal, Quebec.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780/026: ILGWU Local 315 Minutes 5780/027: ILGWU Local 205 Minutes 5780/028: ILGWU Montreal locals Minutes 5780/029: ILGWU Montreal Dress Joint Board Minutes 5780/030: ILGWU Montreal Joint Council Minutes 5780/116: ILGWU Montreal Joint Board Records 5780/117: ILGWU Quebec Joint Council Records
Women's clothing industry -- United States; Women's clothing industry -- Quebec (Province) -- Montreal; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Labor unions -- Clothing workers -- Quebec (Province) -- Montreal; Clothing workers -- United States; Clothing workers -- Quebec (Province) -- Montreal; Industrial relations -- United States; Industrial relations -- Quebec (Province) -- Montreal; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 262 (Montreal (Quebec))
5490743
- Dressmakers minutes, 1943-1963 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  English and French. Attendance sheets, Executive, Joint Board, and General Membership meetings
- Pressers minutes. Vol.1, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  English and French. Attendance sheets, Membership and Executive Meetings
- Pressers minutes. Vol.2, 1947-1949 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Pressers minutes. Vol.3, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Pressers minutes. Vol.4, 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Pressers minutes. Vol.5, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Pressers minutes. Vol.6, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  English and French. Attendance sheets, Membership and Executive Meetings, and Business Agent Reports
- Pressers minutes. Vol.7, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Pressers minutes. Vol.8, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Pressers minutes. Vol.9, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Pressers minutes. Vol.10, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  English and French. Membership and Executive Meetings
- Pressers minutes. Vol.11, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Welfare Fund Committee (Box 3, Folder 1)
  French. Meeting minutes and attendance sheets